# Web scraping

## **Data Scientist - Clarabridge**

Aurora, CO - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Web-scraping/225cb97c8e02f3bb

Data Science expert with extensive experience implementing machine learning algorithms for research and development. 3+ Years conducting NLP based analysis for Fortune 500 companies. Interdisciplinary skillset with consulting, project management, and marketing roles.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **Data Scientist**

Clarabridge - Washington, DC - September 2014 to Present

Strategic data scientist and project manager for Sales Operations & Marketing. Develop original predictive models using machine learning and data-analysis to help secure high-value PR placements, analyze web traffic, optimize marketing campaigns, and produce data-driven content.

- 400% more public relations placements- Research featured in the BBC, The Independent, Quartz, Business Insider, Entrepreneur
- 100% gain in website traffic- projects to optimize SEO, social media strategy, google ads
- 50 sales opportunities with 250k ASP created from data science led account based marketing projects
- 25 million documents analyzed using Clarabridge Sentiment & Text Analytics (social web scraping, tweets, facebook posts)
- Generated 35% of total corporate blog traffic with data driven content and visualization

### Consultant

Walmart, Verizon, and Charles Schwab - Washington, DC - October 2012 to August 2014

Lead implementation consultant responsible for delivery of services and strategic oversight to SaaS Enterprise level customers. Insights development & program management for several clients including Scottrade, Walmart, Verizon, and Charles Schwab.

- Expanded account at Scottrade from 150k ARR to 500k ARR
- Implemented social media insights using text-analytics at Walmart (1+ million ARR)
- Utilized excel, SQL, and Clarabridge analytics platform to conduct sentiment analysis

## Founder /Principal Consultant

MBR Research - Washington, DC - May 2011 to October 2012

Self-started consulting firm focused on building IT solutions for local small business. Engaged in direct sales and design/development, offering customers a variety of services, including web development, marketing, and social media consultancy. Formulated new business strategies utilizing market research to grow revenue.

- Lead web developer and designer
- Utilized CSS, HTML, and PHP for web development
- CMS with Wordpress and Drupal
- Developed and negotiated business contracts
- Engaged in sales pitches and customer relations

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **B.A.** in Political Science

## James Madison University

#### **SKILLS**

MACHINE LEARNING (2 years), SCRAPING (2 years), VISUALIZATION (2 years), SENTIMENT ANALYSIS (1 year), SQL (1 year)

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

## **EXPERTISE**:

Python Copy Writing Sentiment Analysis Javascript NLP Data Visualization Regression Analysis Web Scraping Pandas Time Series Analysis Information Retrieval D3 Machine Learning Google Analytics Numpy Copy Writing Scikit-learn R

#### **RELATED SKILLS & TOOLS**

- Modeling experience with Naïve Bayes, Random Forests, Linear Regression, SVM, Logistic Regression, K-means & K-Neighbors
- Data visualization in D3
- Python Data Stack- Scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy, psycogpg2, statsmodel, numpy, scipy
- Web scraping- Requests, Scrapy, BeautifulSoup
- Ipython Notebook-data
- Advanced Excel
- Git & Github
- SQL
- Basic R & R Studio
- Linux, OSX